you're listening to the cubes English
podcast to download the study guide for
this episode which includes the
transcript detailed vocabulary
explanations real-world examples and a
quiz visit our website Q lips comm see
you l IPS calm hey everybody my name is
Andrew and my name is Marek and you're
listening to Q lips
[Music]
hey more egg hey Andrew how you doing
I'm doing pretty well how about yourself
I'm alright I'm alright
yeah more egg today we're going to talk
about luxury goods and I have kind of a
funny story about how I came to think
that we should record an episode about
luxury goods do you want to hear it
absolutely good well after two years of
struggling with a really terrible slow
old Android phone finally got a new
phone and I bought an iPhone an iPhone X
oh and I'm really happy with this phone
I've only had it for about a week now
but in a way that really disappoints me
I'm so happy because of this phone like
I'm really happy to have it and I I feel
like I shouldn't be so attached to my
phone but it's just such a life changer
it's just made my life better having a
really nice phone that works and when
one of my friends saw that I had a new
iPhone X he mentioned to me you know
Andrew you're not a rich guy you'll
never have a private jet or a mansion
like a billionaire will but the iPhone X
is like one of the only luxury goods
that even the richest guy in the world
you can't get a better phone than that
it's just the top mm line so so I was
thinking about this for a second and I
thought it's true you know I think when
it comes to phones the iPhone is the
best one you can get it's the the top of
the line luxury good and it's available
to a lot of people not just billionaires
and I couldn't think of any other
products like this and this is what got
my mind thinking about luxury goods
so today this is what we'll talk about
we're going to do a chatterbox episode
and to all the listeners out there that
don't know
chatterbox is the series where we have a
totally natural unscripted conversation
we just let the conversation flow in
whichever way it goes and we hope that
by listening in you can improve your
listening fluency and improve your
English now the study guide for this
episode is on our website Q Lipscomb so
if you want to study along with the
study guide head on over to the website
to give it a download okay more let's
chat how about luxury goods luxury goods
when you hear this term luxury goods
what's the first thing that comes to
your mind the first thing that I think
about is really really ridiculously
expensive makeup hmm very interesting
really really ridiculously expensive
making hmm is makeup really that
expensive so if you go to a Sephora
do you know Sephora and ER its makeup
shop I'm assuming yeah it's
international
it has perfume and skincare and tons of
makeup they're huge
okay you can get say like a foundation
for anywhere from $30 which is still
quite a lot to say two hundred and fifty
dollars whoa one hundred and fifty
dollars for foundation yes is this a
huge tub of foundation it's actually
usually smaller than the regular stuff
you could go to a drugstore pharmacy
and get a foundation for $10 Wow
so it's a huge price gap massive there
are so many crazy expensive things
marketed to women so you can easily well
not I mean I wouldn't never have the
money so I could never do this but you
can absolutely put on like fifteen
hundred to two thousand dollars of
products on your face whoa in a day what
yeah yeah I never even considered this
before so if I see a movie star on TV or
a singer you're telling me that they
probably have over a thousand dollars
worth of makeup on their face if they're
using the high-end products which I
assume they would be wearing
interestingly enough you're more likely
to see it on say like instagramers and
that kind of thing than celebrities
because take putting on makeup for four
cameras is actually a bit different and
they usually they can actually use like
really intense kind of more like stage
makeup stuff but yeah I mean like in
their regular lives or people like
famous people on the internet generally
yeah they're probably they probably have
a lot a lot of money finding products on
their body and on their face yeah now
what strikes me as funny is you know
from a male perspective when I think of
luxury goods I think of like high-end
sports cars and
hmm I think for a guy having a luxury
product is all about showing off right
showing off like I Drive a Porsche look
how rich I am look how cool I am right
nothing against guys that drive Porsches
or wear Rolex is I would like these
things too
yeah but I think it's about conspicuous
consumption which is showing other
people that you have money or that you
are wealthy but going back to makeup now
what I'm curious about is
can you even tell if somebody is wearing
this high-end makeup is it noticeable I
I don't think I would be able to tell
but could you tell um no and there's
actually there's quite a lot of there's
an industry built up around people
showing what's called as dupes
duplicates okay things that are you know
a high-end product and then a lower end
or drugstore product it looks exactly
the same a lot of it though you're
talking about conspicuous consumption it
is actually conspicuous consumption not
because you can tell when looking at
someone
what sort of makeup they have on their
face but say in in the washroom when
they're going to go touch up when they
pull out that lipstick does it say
eve-san la on it you know it's that kind
of thing okay al is a lot of these
luxury makeup goods have crazy beautiful
packaging or they're much like higher
quality they're metal or they're all
this kind of stuff you know so you can
you can you still see it it's still
about showing off it's just not as loud
as a car probably literally and but it's
the same thing I mean like a lot of
there's a a lot of luxury goods that
work for any gender are like you know a
t-shirt for 150 bucks or something you
know if you're thinking about like
Lacoste that kind of stuff mm-hmm
you know it's like if you get a pullover
like 200 bucks or something right yes
you know um it's like that branding
thing so it doesn't look all that
different from far away but yeah I don't
know I just
are you at all interested in buying like
a luxury good is there a luxury good
that you would save up for other than
the phone yeah I don't think so you know
like I like vintage watches I like
looking at them when I see them I think
they're really cool I would be super
stoked to one day be
able to afford like a vintage Rolex or
something but I don't think I would save
up for this that would only be something
that I would buy if I were rich or a
sports car like I mentioned a Porsche or
something I'm not opposed to these items
I think they're cool but I don't ever
see me owning one and you know if I
saved up all my money to buy a vintage
Rolex
it would just be ridiculous because the
rest of my outfit is just very plain and
normal person clothes you know and then
to have this super expensive watch it
would be kind of silly but sometimes I
do see people around town you know with
like a really expensive handbag or
something but the rest of their outfit
doesn't look special so I think oh maybe
this person just really really really
wanted to handbag and saved up for a
long time to buy it but is actually not
rich it's funny because I've known a
couple people that had a lot of money
and neither of them actually had any of
this stuff yeah yeah my friend who from
friend of friends from high school who
had you know way too much money um or
his family did and he wore second-hand
clothes yep you know it's it's funny
it's definitely um it's not necessarily
about how much money you actually have
but about how much money you want to
look like you have exactly and there's
two expressions that might be relevant
here old money and new money and so old
money we use to refer to families that
have been wealthy for generations and
generations you could think of like
aristocrats or successful business
families that have just been able to
carry their wealth forward from one
generation to the next and I think we
consider people that are old money to be
less flashy like sometimes like your
friend
you don't actually you can't actually
tell that these people are rich just
because they're I mean it's different
for everybody but this is just my
general sense is that they're not as
flashy whereas with new money new money
you could think of somebody who maybe
won the lottery or suddenly became rich
maybe an athlete that suddenly went from
being poor to having a multi-million
dollar contract and then they just go
all out
they're like I got money now let's spend
it right and they buy everything and
yeah so I think there's a distinction
depending on how you got your wealth how
long you've been wealthy this might
determine how you spend your money and
what kind of products you buy with that
money absolutely and as a note old money
usually looks down on new money it's
true yeah so it's the edges like with
this distinction it's that usually old
money is like the thing you want to be
it's classier it's um just more the
correct way to be rich which is so
ridiculous that's more refined more
refined yes exactly as opposed to new
money which is like flashy and you know
show off kind of show uh fee and that
kind of thing show off you see show
everywhere that came to my mind was
braggadocious which is a word that I
don't rarely use braggadocious but but
that is a word it's a great word it's
fun to say to braggadocious boasting
right you're boasting if you're new
money perhaps unrestrained in a in an
unbecoming way sort of thing yeah Morag
just before we finish here I want to ask
you one quick question and that is okay
if money wasn't an issue for you what
kind of luxury products would you like
to buy if any mm
I would want as this is going a bit
crazy um I would want it I would want a
car I have always wanted a 1971 Jaguar
e-type mm classy
yeah yeah I've always wanted that car I
remember about 10 to 12 years ago they
cost about $200,000 so who knows I'm
never getting that car maybe one day
maybe one yeah when I win the lottery a
big lottery a big luck yeah yeah well
everybody that about brings us to the
end of today's show and we're very
curious what do you think about luxury
goods
do you own any luxury goods or if you
could buy a luxury good a luxury product
what would you buy it would it be car or
watch or some makeup a handbag what
would you like to buy send us an email
our address is contact at Q lips comm or
visit us on Facebook or Twitter and send
us a message that way okay that's it for
today we'll talk to you next time
bye everybody goodbye the best way to
study with Q lips is by becoming a Q
lips member when you become a key lips
member you will get full transcripts
detailed vocabulary explanations and
quizzes for each episode visit Q lips
calm
see you l i p s dot-com to sign up and
become a member